



# **Chung Ho Duc**

**Date of birth:** 12/06/1990 **Gender:** Male **\Congress Phone:** (+49) 017636843053

Email: <a href="mailto:chunghoduc1206@gmail.com">chunghoduc1206@gmail.com</a>

• Home: Soproner Straße 4, 99427 Weimar (Germany)

#### **ABOUT MYSELF**

I am an enthusiastic software development engineer with more than 10 years of experiences working in software development industry. My strength is designing and developing back-end systems and apis using various of languages and patterns

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Senior Software Engineer**

**Teko Vietnam Technology JSC** [ 03/2017 - 09/2022 ]

City: Hanoi | Country: Vietnam

#### **Team Leader:**

- Led development teams of 6-8 members to complete two key projects, exceeding the KPI target by 120-140%.
- Successfully trained seven internship students into skilled employees for the company.

### **Software Engineer:**

- Design architecture built the core and contributed to the development phase of the Logistic microservice in an ERP that reduced average delivery time for orders by 25%, decreased wrong or missing delivery cases by 95%, and saved 50% of the time used by warehouse operators in assigning delivery employees.
- Design architecture built the core and contributed to the development phase of the Finance reporting microservice in an ERP that generated finance reports 80% faster and reduced the time required for reconciliation by 40%.

#### **Scrum Master:**

- Successfully applied Scrum methodology to team operations, leading to a 75% reduction in overdue tasks, a 30% increase in productivity, and a 35% decrease in QA-phase bugs within six months.
- Served as a Scrum Master, facilitating all Scrum ceremonies, including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, reviews, and retrospectives. Provided all support needed by team members to achieve the achievements mentioned above.

Tech Stack: Microservices, CQRS, Redis, MySql, Python, Go, Kafka, Gitlab CI, MySQL, UML

## **Senior Software Engineer (Remote)**

**TIPEME HOLDINGS PTY LTD** [ 11/2016 - 04/2020 ]

City: Brisbane | Country: Australia

## **Software Development:**

- Designed and developed over 50 APIs for TipeME, a social network application, enhancing user privacy and AR features, leading to a 30% increase in user engagement.
- Improved, maintained, and refactored 70 legacy APIs from previous developers, reducing system failures by 95% and enhancing API loading times by 100-400%

## **System Optimization:**

- Improved system performance by 40% by optimizing database queries and refactoring code.
- Implementing caching and tuning SQL queries to ensure API p90 loading times remained under 100ms
- Applied a CDN for media resources and a solution for media compressing, improving in-app loading times by 70% and reducing user data usage by 40%.

Tech stack: PHP, XMPP, Redis, Apache, PostgreSQL, socket.IO, AWS

#### **Technical Leader**

**Vietnam Unity App Studio Co. Itd, Hanoi** [ 09/2014 - 09/2016 ]

City: Hanoi | Country: Vietnam

#### **Team Leader:**

• Led and mentored development teams of 5-6 members, ensuring successful project delivery and effective collaboration in Sembang Chat and EyeProtec projects.

## **Software Engineer:**

- Initiated the codebase and designed over 100 APIs for Sembang Chat, a Malaysian social network. Led a team of 5 developers to complete the project and achieved 100,000 active users within three months of launch.
- Design architecture and build the core of EyeProtec, an application that reports natural disasters, missing persons, personal emergencies, and terrorist activities. The project processed over 4,000 emergency reports per month and broadcasted around 1,000 natural disaster warnings to approximately 50,000 users per month.

Tech stack: PHP, XMPP, Redis, Apache, MySQL, jQuery, socket.IO

# Software engineer

**Septeni Technology Co. Ltd** [ 07/2013 – 09/2014 ]

City: Hanoi | Country: Vietnam

# **Software Engineer:**

- Contributed to the PYXIS project, leading to a 25% increase in the effectiveness of Facebook ad campaigns and approximately 10% cost reduction for users.
- Independently designed solution and architect for the Autobid project, which helps users to automatically bid the best price for a Facebook ads campaign with a designed target and time frame. The project helped users to save an average amount of 25% total budget spent for Facebook ads

# **Development Methodologies and Practices:**

- Successfully applied TDD (Test-Driven Development), reducing bug occurrences by 30%.
- Successfully applied Scrum methodology ensuring iterative progress and continuous delivery of features.

Tech stack: PHP, Redis, Apache, MySQL, jQuery

# Software developer

**5land Technology JSC** [ 04/2012 – 07/2013 ]

City: Hanoi | Country: Vietnam

### **Software Engineer:**

- Developed a comprehensive data crawling system that collected over 200,000 real estate trading records, improving the accuracy of the price prediction system to within a 15% margin of error.
- Built a user-friendly website for Real Estate trading that attracted 10,000 unique visitors within the first three months.

Tech stack: PHP, Apache, MySQL, jQuery

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

## **BSc Computer Science**

**VNU University of Engineering and Technology** [ 10/2008 – 08/2012 ]

City: Hanoi | Country: Vietnam | Website: <a href="https://uet.vnu.edu.vn/en/">https://uet.vnu.edu.vn/en/</a> | Field(s) of study: Computer Science | Thesis: Composition of models in Aspect Oriented Modeling

## **MSc Computer Science for Digital Media**

**Bauhaus University Weimar** [ 10/2021 – Current ]

City: Weimar | Country: Germany | Website: https://www.uni-weimar.de

## **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING C1 READING C2 WRITING C1

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION** B2 **SPOKEN INTERACTION** B2 **SPOKEN PRODUCTION** A2 **SPOKEN INTERACTION** A2

German

LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user